Guide to the Benjamin Newton Duke Papers, 1834-1969, bulk 1890-1929. RL.00328
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Financial, 1876-1878, 1884-1936, and undated; 30.5 Linear Feet
  - General, 1876-1878, 1884-1936, and undated
    - Statements: Durham, NC monthly expenditures (J. E. Stagg, agent), 1902 (Box 87, Folder 19)
    - Statements: Durham, NC monthly expenditures (J. E. Stagg, agent), 1903 (Box 87, Folder 20)
    - Statements: Durham, NC monthly expenditures (J. E. Stagg, agent), 1904 (Box 87, Folder 21)
    - Statements: Durham, NC monthly expenditures (J. E. Stagg, agent), 1905 (Box 87, Folder 22)
    - Statements: Durham, NC monthly expenditures (J. E. Stagg, agent), 1906 (Box 87, Folder 23)
    - Statements: Durham, NC monthly expenditures (J. E. Stagg, agent), 1907 (Box 87, Folder 24)
    - Statements: Durham, NC monthly expenditures (E. A. Childs, agent), 1908-1924; 17 folders (Box 88)
    - Statements: New York, NY monthly expenditures (R. B. Arrington, agent), 1906 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Statements: New York, NY monthly expenditures (R. B. Arrington, agent), 1907 (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Statements: New York, NY monthly expenditures (R. B. Arrington, agent), 1908 (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Statements: New York, NY monthly expenditures (R. B. Arrington, agent), 1909 (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Statements: New York, NY monthly expenditures (A. H. Sands, Jr., agent), 1913 November-1914 February (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - Statements: New York, NY monthly expenditures (A. H. Sands, Jr., agent), 1915 January-June (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Statements: Assets and Liabilities, Benjamin N. Duke, circa 1913 (Box 89, Folder 7)
    - Statements: Benjamin N. Duke in account with others, 1905-1906, 1909, 1914 (Box 89, Folder 8)
    - Statements: others in account with Benjamin N. Duke, 1893, 1905, 1907, 1909-1917 (Box 89, Folder 9)
    - Statements: James B. Duke, miscellaneous, 1913-1914 (Box 89, Folder 10)
    - Statements: Nanaline H. Duke, miscellaneous, 1913 and undated (Box 89, Folder 11)
    - Statements: miscellaneous financial worksheets, 1913-1914 (Box 89, Folder 12)
    - Taxes: American Cotton Manufacturing Co., 1902-1905 (Box 89, Folder 13)
    - Taxes: real estate and personal property, Durham and Orange County, NC: Benjamin N. Duke, 1914-1926 (Box 89, Folder 14)
    - Taxes: real estate and personal property, Durham County, NC: James B. Duke, 1914-1918 (Box 89, Folder 15)
    - Tithe accounts, Benjamin N. Duke and Washington Duke, 1897 (Box 89, Folder 16)
    - Trial balances: Angier B. Duke, 1914 December-1915 May (Box 89, Folder 17)
    - Trial balances: Benjamin N. Duke, 1912-1914 (Box 89, Folder 18)
    - Trial balances: James B. Duke, 1912 (Box 89, Folder 19)
    - Trial balances: James B. Duke, 1913 (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Trial balances: James B. Duke, 1914 (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Trinity College: statement of building fund, 1911 April 1 (Box 90, Folder 3)
      The statement details the receipts and disbursements for academic building, administrative building, and East Dormitory in March 1911.
    - W. Duke, Sons and Company cashbook, 1891; Trial balances: Washington Duke and Benjamin N. Duke, 1893-1897, 1 Volumes (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - Banking, 1891-1924
    A related deposit slip register is located in the James Buchanan Duke papers, Financial series.
    The Banking subseries contains deposit slips, check stubs, and other banking records for the accounts of Benjamin N. Duke and his family.
    - Bank accounts: deposits, notices, statements, 1891-1892, 1896; 1 folders (Box 91)
    - Bank accounts: deposits, notices, statements, 1901 May-1908 December; 10 folders (Box 91)
    - Bank accounts: deposits, notices, statements, 1909-1912; 13 folders (Box 92)
    - Bank accounts: deposits, notices, statements, 1913-1915; 11 folders (Box 93)
    - Bank accounts: deposits, notices, statements, 1916-1924 March, and undated; 11 folders (Box 94)
    - Bank accounts: Union Exchange National Bank (New York agent account), 1912 May-1913 November (Box 94)
    - Bank accounts: Guaranty Trust Company of New York (Sarah P. Duke account), 1916-1922 (Box 94)
    - Voucher records: Farmers' Loan and Trust Company, 1901 June-1907 March (Box 94)
    - Check registers: New York agent's account, 1917-1918; 2 Volumes (Box 95)
    - Check stubs: Biddle, Anthony J. Drexel, Jr., 1919; 1 Volumes (Box 96)
    - Check stubs: Biddle, Mary Duke, 1915-1918; 1 Volumes (Box 96)
    - Check stubs: Duke, Angier B., 1914-1917; 4 Volumes (Box 96)
    - Check stubs: Duke, Angier B., 1917-1918; 4 Volumes (Box 97)
    - Check stubs: Duke, Benjamin N., 1896 September-1901 August (Box 94)
    - Check stubs: Duke, Benjamin N., 1901-1918; 4 Volumes (Box 98)
    - Check stubs: New York agent's account, 1913-1915; 4 Volumes (Box 99)
    - Check stubs: New York agent's account, 1914-1916; 4 Volumes (Box 100)
    - Check stubs: New York agent's account, 1917; 1 Volumes (Box 101)
    - Deposit slip register: J. B. Duke and B.N. Duke, 1915-1918 (Box 102)
  - Investments, 1891-1923
    The Investments subseries contains account statements, correspondence, ledgers, stock certificates, and other materials documenting the financial investments of Benjamin N. Duke and family. It includes monthly financial statements from the numerous New York brokerage firms that Duke engaged to manage his investments, including Dominick and Dickerman, Moore and Schley, Halsted and Harrison, Newberger, Henderson and Loeb, and Daniel O'Dell and Company. To a lesser extent, the subseries includes statements for investments made through Duke's brokerage accounts by family, friends, and business associates.
    The brokerage account correspondence includes discussion of stock market trends and the financial impact of world events, such as the Spanish American War and World War I. Also included are letters from Joseph Catlin, who negotiated stock sales on behalf of the Riverside Cotton Mills. Southern Investment Company of Canada materials include correspondence related to the incorporation of the company and activities in the Saguenay River area of Quebec.
    Outgoing brokerage account and other financial correspondence is located in the Correspondence series, Letterbooks subseries.
    - Brokerage accounts: correspondence, 1891-1897 May; 14 folders (Box 103)
    - Brokerage accounts: correspondence, 1897 June-1900 July; 14 folders (Box 104)
    - Brokerage accounts: correspondence, 1900 August-1903 February; 13 folders (Box 105)
    - Brokerage accounts: correspondence, 1903 March-1906 April; 14 folders (Box 106)
    - Brokerage accounts: correspondence, 1905 June 27; oversize (Box 161, Folder 5)
      Dominick to B. N. Duke: Kansas City, Mexico and Orient Railway prospectus.
    - Brokerage accounts: correspondence, 1906 May-1910; 14 folders (Box 107)
    - Brokerage accounts: correspondence, 1911-1914; 14 folders (Box 108)
    - Brokerage accounts: correspondence, 1915-1918 January, 1923, and undated; 13 folders (Box 109)
    - Brokerage accounts: Moore & Schley code books #2, #3, 1906; 2 Volumes (Box 110)
    - Brokerage accounts: statements, 1896-1900; 14 folders (Box 111)
    - Brokerage accounts: statements, 1901 January-1905 February; 15 folders (Box 112)
    - Brokerage accounts: statements, 1905 March-1906 December; 14 folders (Box 113)
    - Brokerage accounts: statements, 1907 January-1910 January; 14 folders (Box 114)
    - Brokerage accounts: statements, 1910 February-1911 September; 12 folders (Box 115)
    - Brokerage accounts: statements, 1911 October-1912 August; 12 folders (Box 116)
    - Brokerage accounts: statements, 1912 September-1913 June; 12 folders (Box 117)
    - Brokerage accounts: statements, 1913 July-1914 December; 18 folders (Box 118)
    - Brokerage accounts: statements, 1913; 3 folders; oversize, 1 of 3 (Box 121, Folder 1)
    - Brokerage accounts: statements, 1913; oversize, 2 of 3 (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - Brokerage accounts: statements, 1913; oversize, 3 of 3 (Box 121, Folder 3)
    - Brokerage accounts: statements, 1914; oversize, 1 of 4 (Box 121, Folder 4)
    - Brokerage accounts: statements, 1914; oversize, 2 of 4 (Box 121, Folder 5)
    - Brokerage accounts: statements, 1914; oversize, 3 of 4 (Box 121, Folder 6)
    - Brokerage accounts: statements, 1914; oversize, 4 of 4 (Box 121, Folder 7)
    - Brokerage accounts: statements, 1915 January-1916 January; 13 folders (Box 119)
    - Brokerage accounts: statements, 1916 February-1918 and undated; 16 folders (Box 120)
    - Real estate: account statements [unidentified rental property], 1914 May-1915 April; oversize (Box 123, Folder 9)
    - Real estate: Durham Realty Corporation: account statements, 1913 July-1915 and undated; 2 folders (Box 124)
      These documents include statements of rental receipts for account of B. N. Duke, income statements, and other accounting materials related to the management of Duke's rental properties in New York. The properties represented include Marc Antony Apartments, Prince Humbert Apartments, The Paterno, and 200 West 58th Street apartments.
    - Real estate: Durham Realty Corporation: rent statements, 1913 July-December (Box 124)
      Statements are included for each tenant of Marc Antony Apartments, New York, NY, showing rents and utilities paid for each month.
    - Real estate: Florida: attorney fees and tax receipts, 1888-1902 (Box 124)
    - Real estate, miscellaneous statements, 1911-1915 and undated (Box 124)
    - Receipts, American Tobacco Company stock: James B. Duke, trustee, to Mary E. Lyon, Brodie L. Duke, Benjamin N. Duke, Washington Duke, and George W. Watts, 1896 (Box 124)
    - Record of stock dividends: volume 1, 1892-1918; 1 of 3 (Box 121, Folder 8)
    - Record of stock dividends: volume 1, 1892-1918; 2 of 3 (Box 121, Folder 9)
    - Record of stock dividends: volume 1, 1892-1918; 3 of 3 (Box 121, Folder 10)
    - Record of stock dividends: volume 2, 4 folders (Box 122)
      Includes the investments of Angier B.Duke, Mary Duke Biddle, Sarah P. Duke, Anthony J. Drexel Biddle, Jr., and Cordelia Biddle Duke.
    - Record of stock dividends: volume 3 (Box 122)
    - Southern Investment Company of Canada, 1913 January-1914 April; 10 folders (Box 124)
    - Southern Investment Company of Canada, 1914 May-1915 August; 16 folders (Box 125)
    - Southern Investment Company of Canada, 1915 September-1916 March and undated; 4 folders (Box 126)
    - Southern Investment Company of Delaware, 1913-1914 (Box 126)
    - Southern Investment Company of Delaware, 1915-1916 (Box 126)
    - Southern Investment Company of New Jersey, 1912 (Box 126)
    - Southern Investment Company of New Jersey, 1913-1915 (Box 126)
    - Stock journal, 1899-1901 (Box 127)
    - Stock ledger, 1899-1901 (Box 128)
    - Stock certificates, 1887-1917 (Box 126)
    - Stock transactions (by broker), 1902, 1913-1915, and undated (Box 126)
    - Stock transactions (by broker), 1914 and undated; oversize (Box 123, Folder 10)
    - Stock transactions (by stock), 1908-1914; 1 of 2 (Box 126)
    - Stock transactions (by stock), 1908-1914; 2 of 2 (Box 126)
    - Stock transactions (by stock), 1917-1919 and undated (Box 126)
    - Stock transactions (by stock), 1914-1915; oversize (Box 161, Folder 6)
      Account sheets for James B. Duke and Southern Investment Company [of Canada?]
    - Stock transactions: William H. Butler account, tobacco stemmer stock purchase, circa 1913 (Box 126)
- Legal, 1834-1928 and undated; 1 Linear Feet
  Materials related to properties owned by Benjamin Duke appear first and are grouped according to geographic location. The rest of the series is arranged alphabetically by major individual or entity involved.
  A majority of the documents in the Legal series pertain to property transactions of Benjamin Newton Duke and other individuals in Orange County, NC and Durham, NC. Property deeds dating from 1838 show changes in ownership of land that Duke eventually purchased. Other papers include architectural contracts, plans and specifications, trust indentures, a legal brief, copies of the wills of Benjamin N. Duke and Washington Duke, and materials related to the execution of the estates of Angier B. Duke and Benjamin N. Duke.
  - Deed: Asheville, NC, 1890 (Box 134, Folder 1)
    Includes an abstract of title and notes of attornies W. W. Fuller and Cobb & Merrimon.
  - Deeds: Durham, NC, 1874-1879 (Box 134, Folder 2)
  - Deeds: Durham, NC, 1880-1884 (Box 134, Folder 3)
  - Deeds: Durham, NC, 1889-1890 (Box 134, Folder 4)
  - Deeds: Durham, NC, 1891-1893 (Box 134, Folder 5)
    Includes an 1892 trust agreement among Duke family members for the use and maintenance of the mausoleum in Durham (now Maplewood) Cemetery.
  - Deeds: Durham, NC, 1894-1899 (Box 134, Folder 6)
  - Deeds: Durham, NC, 1900 (Box 134, Folder 7)
  - Deeds: Durham, NC, 1902-1905, 1907 (Box 134, Folder 8)
  - Deeds: Durham, NC, 1914 (Box 134, Folder 9)
  - Deeds: Orange County, NC, 1834, 1835, 1845, 1850, 1860, 1864 (Box 134, Folder 10)
  - Deeds: Orange County, NC, 1871-1877 (Box 134, Folder 11)
  - Deeds: Orange County, NC, 1880-1885 (Box 134, Folder 12)
  - Deeds: Orange County, NC, 1886-1893 (Box 134, Folder 13)
  - Deeds: Orange County, NC, 1894-1899 (Box 134, Folder 14)
  - Deeds: Orange County, NC, 1900-1902 (Box 134, Folder 15)
  - Deeds: Orange County, NC, 1904-1905 (Box 134, Folder 16)
  - Deeds: Orange County, NC, 1906-1909 (Box 134, Folder 17)
  - Deeds: Orange County, NC, 1910-1912 (Box 134, Folder 18)
  - Deeds: Orange County, NC, 1916, 1918 (Box 134, Folder 19)
  - Deeds: Raleigh, NC, 1891, 1897 (Box 134, Folder 20)
  - Dallas Cable Railway: agreement, 1891 (Box 135, Folder 1)
  - Doris Duke Trust: Indenture and deed of trust, with additions, circa 1925 (Box 135, Folder 2)
  - Duke, Angier B.: estate (distribution), 1926 (Box 135, Folder 3)
  - Duke, Benjamin N.: agreement and specifications for construction of stable, Durham, NC (H. Blauvelt, architect), 1901 (Box 135, Folder 4)
  - Duke, Benjamin N.: agreements and land plat related to property at E. 76th Street and 5th Avenue, New York, NY, 1902, 1906 (Box 135, Folder 5)
  - Duke, Benjamin N.: agreements related to Chapel Hill Street residence ("The Terrace"), Durham, NC, 1887, 1893, 1909 (Box 135, Folder 6)
  - Duke, Benjamin N.: architectural plans for stables, Durham, NC (H. Blauvelt, architect), 1901; oversize blueprints, 1 of 2 (Box 161, Folder 3)
  - Duke, Benjamin N.: architectural plans for stables, Durham, NC (H. Blauvelt, architect), 1901; oversize blueprints, 2 of 2 (Box 161, Folder 4)
  - Duke, Benjamin N.: land plat of property conveyed by R. P. Strahorn, located near University Station (Orange County, NC), 1907; oversize blueprint (Box 123, Folder 16)
  - Duke, Benjamin N.: land plat of Orange County, NC, property, drafted by N. A. Ramsey, circa 1897; oversize (Box 123, Folder 11)
  - Duke, Benjamin N.: land plats of property at 89th St. and 5th Ave., New York, NY, undated (Box 135, Folder 7)
  - Duke, Benjamin N.: property leases, 1908, 1912, 1913 (Box 135, Folder 8)
  - Duke, Benjamin N.: trust agreement with George G. Allen, Robert L. Flowers, and Alex. H. Sands, Jr. for various institutions of higher education and the Angier B. Duke Memorial, Inc., 1926 (Box 135, Folder 9)
  - Duke, Benjamin N.: will and estate, 1926-1930 (Box 135, Folder 10)
    The estate documents include an appraisal of real and personal property at 2 East 89th Street, 1009 5th Avenue, and 535 5th Avenue in New York, NY; a power of attorney from Sarah P. Duke to Mary Duke Biddle; and a memorandum written by Anthony J. Drexel Biddle, Jr.
  - Duke, Benjamin N. and George W. Watts: agreements with Southern Railway Company, 1900, 1902 (Box 135, Folder 11)
  - Duke, Benjamin N. and George W. Watts: deeds and receipts for tobacco purchase from Edmunds, Bass & Co., 1894 (Box 135, Folder 12)
  - Duke, Benjamin N. and others: agreements and contracts, miscellaneous, 1891, 1895-1901, 1905-1906 (Box 135, Folder 13)
  - Duke, Benjamin N. and others: agreements and contracts, miscellaneous, 1908-1914 and undated (Box 135, Folder 14)
  - Duke, Benjamin N. and others: complaints, petitions, and summonses, 1891, 1903, 1907-1911 (Box 135, Folder 15)
    Legal documents include a printed copy of "Complaint and Summons, Richard H. Wright against James B. Duke, Benjamin N. Duke, Brodie L. Duke, George W. Watts" (New York Supreme Court).
  - Duke, Benjamin N. and others: land plats, Durham, NC, 1897, 1912, undated (Box 135, Folder 16)
  - Duke, Washington: agreement with Van Gunden Granite and Marble Works for construction of Duke family mausoleum, Durham, NC, 1893 (Box 135, Folder 17)
  - Duke, Washington: instruments of gift to Benjamin N. Duke and Mary W. Stagg (Mamie L. Stagg), 1900 December 11 (Box 135, Folder 18)
  - Duke, Washington: trust agreements with Fidelity Bank for domestic workers, 1904 October 10 (Box 135, Folder 19)
    Beneficiaries of this agreement include Albert Armstrong (coachman), Caroline Barnes (servant), Joseph Bynum (butler), Frank Davis (yardman), and Addie Evans (cook).
  - Duke, Washington: trust agreements with Fidelity Bank for Annie Duke and Robert Duke, 1904 October 10 (Box 135, Folder 20)
  - Duke, Washington: trust agreements with Fidelity Bank for George L. Lyon and Buchanan Lyon, 1900 December 11 (Box 135, Folder 21)
  - Duke, Washington: will, 1905; typescript copy (Box 135, Folder 22)
  - Fidelity Bank, Durham, NC: schedule bond and continuation certificates, 1894-1905 (Box 135, Folder 23)
  - Guanajuato River Mining Company: agreements, 1903 (Box 135, Folder 24)
  - Kimball Town Company (Kimball, TN): deeds and complaint, 1890 (Box 135, Folder 25)
  - National Drama Corporation: property lease, 1915 October 29 (Box 135, Folder 26)
  - Southern Conservatory of Music: architectural blueprints of proposed addition, circa 1899; oversize (Oversize-folder 3)
  - Southern Conservatory of Music: specifications for heating and lighting, 1899 and undated (Box 135, Folder 27)
  - Trinity College: specifications and land plat for construction of stone wall around campus, 1916 (Box 135, Folder 28)
  - [West Durham] Methodist Church: architectural specifications for addition, 1897 (Box 135, Folder 29)
  - Worth, W. H. and others: surety bond, 1897, 1901 (Box 135, Folder 30)
- Business, 1880, 1890-1919, and undated; 2.5 Linear Feet
  The materials are arranged alphabetically by industry, with miscellaneous businesses listed alphabetically by name at the end of the series.
  The bulk of the Business series consists of published and unpublished periodic financial reports from businesses in which Benjamin N. Duke had a financial interest, as well as investment prospectuses and circulars. A limited number of corporate records, such as acts of incorporation, bylaws and meeting minutes, also appear and are noted in the contents list. The industries represented include banking, cotton and textiles, railroads, power and utilities, and tobacco.
  - Banks and trusts: American Trust Company, 1907-1914 (Box 129)
  - Banks and trusts: Bank of Harnett, Duke [Erwin], NC, 1906-1915 (Box 129)
  - Banks and trusts: Canal Bank & Trust Company, New Orleans, 1914-1916 (Box 129)
  - Banks and trusts: Chatham and Phenix National Bank of New York, 1911-1914 (Box 129)
  - Banks and trusts: Citizens National Bank of Durham, NC, 1905-1911 (Box 129)
  - Banks and trusts: Fidelity Bank of Durham, NC, 1905-1919 (Box 129)
  - Banks and trusts: Fidelity Bank of Durham, NC: plaque, 1922 (Box 129)
  - Banks and trusts: First National Bank of Winston, NC: balance sheet, 1893 July 5; oversize (Box 123, Folder 15)
  - Banks and trusts: German-American National Bank of New Orleans, 1911-1913 (Box 129)
  - Banks and trusts: Guaranty Trust Company of New York, 1910-1915 (Box 129)
  - Banks and trusts: Hanover National Bank of New York, 1912-1914 (Box 129)
  - Banks and trusts: Mellon National Bank, 1913-1914 (Box 129)
  - Banks and trusts: Morton Trust Company, 1900-1910 (Box 129)
  - Banks and trusts: National Bank of Commerce in New York, 1912-1916 (Box 129)
  - Banks and trusts: Second National Bank, City of New York, 1908-1915 (Box 129)
  - Banks and trusts: Second National Bank of Somerville, New Jersey, 1912-1915 (Box 129)
  - Banks and trusts: Union Exchange Bank, 1903-1914 (Box 129)
  - Banks and trusts: miscellaneous, 1900, 1906-1915, and undated; 2 folders (Box 129)
  - Cotton and textiles: Asheville Cotton Mills, 1895-1896, 1898, 1902 (Box 129)
  - Cotton and textiles: Cannon Manufacturing Company, 1896, 1898-1912 (Box 129)
  - Cotton and textiles: Commonwealth Cotton Manufacturing Company, 1898-1905 (Box 129)
  - Cotton and textiles: Cooleemee Cotton Mills, 1901, 1905 (Box 129)
  - Cotton and textiles: Durham Cotton Manufacturing Company, 1894, 1896-1901, 1906 (Box 130)
  - Cotton and textiles: Lily Mills, 1902 (Box 130)
  - Cotton and textiles: Little River Manufacturing Company, 1908-1914 (Box 130)
  - Cotton and textiles: Mayo Mills, 1897-1898, 1903, 1910 (Box 130)
  - Cotton and textiles: Nantucket Mills, 1901-1904 (Box 130)
  - Cotton and textiles: Pearl Cotton Mills, 1898, 1900-1902 (Box 130)
  - Cotton and textiles: Proximity Manufacturing Company, 1901-1907 (Box 130)
  - Cotton and textiles: Riverside Cotton Mills, Danville, VA, 1892, 1894, 1898-1899 (Box 130)
  - Cotton and textiles: Rocky Mount Mills, 1895-1898 (Box 130)
  - Cotton and textiles: Spray Cotton Mills, 1911, 1915 (Box 130)
  - Cotton and textiles: miscellaneous, 1894, 1897, 1902, 1907-1915 and undated; 2 folders (Box 130)
  - Insurance: Dixie Fire Insurance Company, 1907-1916 (Box 130)
  - Insurance: miscellaneous, 1906, 1908, 1914-1915 and undated (Box 130)
  - Mining and foundries: American Type Founders Company, 1898, 1903-1904, 1907-1914 (Box 130)
  - Mining and foundries: Jim Butler Tonopah Mining Company, 1902?, 1904-1915 (Box 130)
  - Mining and foundries: Republic Iron and Steel Company, 1899, 1903-1904, 1909, 1913 (Box 130)
  - Mining and foundries: miscellaneous, 1902-1915, and undated (Box 130)
  - Power and utilities: Asheville Ice and Coal Co., 1895, 1898-1899 (Box 130)
  - Power and utilities: Asheville Ice and Coal Co.: act to incorporate, 1891 May 2 (Box 130)
  - Power and utilities: Carolina Power and Light Co., 1916 (Box 130)
  - Power and utilities: Circle Power Company: check stubs, stock certificates, 1908, 1910 (Box 130)
  - Power and utilities: Georgia Railway and Power Company, 1914-1915 (Box 130)
  - Power and utilities: Great Falls Power Company, 1910-1913 (Box 130)
  - Power and utilities: Southern Power Company, 1909-1914 (Box 130)
  - Power and utilities: Project plans for Pigeon River Power Plant, NC, 1923; oversize (Box 161, Folder 7)
  - Power and utilities: map of hydroelectric power [transmission lines?], North Carolina and South Carolina, circa 1900-1910s; oversize blueprint (Box 161, Folder 2)
    The map is labeled in pencil on back: "Lookout Shoals."
  - Power and utilities: miscellaneous, 1893-1896, 1911-1915 (Box 130)
  - Railroads: Durham and Southern Railway Company: Durham Station freight business statements, 1907 April-August (Box 130)
  - Railroads: Durham and Southern Railway Company: monthly earnings and expenditures statements, 1906 September-1907 February (Box 130)
  - Railroads: Durham and Southern Railway Company: weekly estimated earnings reports, 1908-1910; 3 folders (Box 130)
  - Railroads: Durham and Southern Railway Company: weekly estimated earnings reports, 1911-1916; 5 folders (Box 131)
  - Railroads: Hudson and Manhattan Railroad Company, 1911-1916 (Box 131)
  - Railroads: Kansas City, Mexico and Orient Railway Company, 1905-1914 and undated (Box 131)
  - Railroads: Seaboard Air Line Railway, 1906, 1909, 1912, 1915 (Box 131)
  - Railroads: Seaboard Air Line Railway: banquet program (B.N. Duke presentation copy), 1900 (Box 131)
  - Railroads: Southern Pacific Company, 1909-1914 (Box 131)